<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>orange peels and tyre squeels</title>
 <link href="https://adilw3nomad.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://adilw3nomad.github.io//"/>
 <updated>2022-04-25T09:33:03-05:00</updated>
 <id>https://adilw3nomad.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>adilw3nomad</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hardest decision of my career</title>
   <link href="https://adilw3nomad.github.io//2022/04/25/hardest-decision-of-my-career/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-25T09:29:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://adilw3nomad.github.io/2022/04/25/hardest-decision-of-my-career</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-most-difficult-decision-of-my-career&quot;&gt;The most difficult decision of my career&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I resigned from my position as an engineer at one of the fastest unicorns in the industry; a company last valued at 7.4 billion dollars. A place that has revolutionised the outdated ideas we cling to about communication, offices, and the imaginary lines that define where and how we work. It’s a place that exists in cyberspace, (albeit not as cool as the one in Neuromancer), where I honed my craft and was applauded not only for my achievements, but for being authentically, unapologetically, me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made friends with people I had never met, and worked alongside them at breakneck speed, providing a service that was invaluable in bringing people closer together when it was most needed. Alongside some of the most brilliant minds in our industry, I was exposed to a cornucopia of new perspectives, new models of thinking, new ways of working, soaking it all up like a sponge in a fish tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My identity as an engineer is entwined with that of Hopin to a large extent, something I am both proud and grateful for. Like a mirror, it showed me aspects of my self I was unaware of, in particular my interests in the nature of collaboration, culture and compassion in the practice of software development.  The immense and rapid growth Hopin experienced, from 80 employees when I joined to 1000,  gave me a front seat view to study these things in “production” so to speak, to tweak and adjust even the most minute details in my own pod, finding that much of the industry (as I have experienced it), ignore one of the most crucial aspects of a successful group, team, or company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by many at Hopin, I have found the courage to let go of what is safe and run head first into a new adventure; one where I can begin to share the things I’ve learnt that work, and validate new ideas around how to effectively and easily help people scale their engineering teams. Unfortunately (well fortunately really), Hopin has matured to a point where I can’t have the type of impact which I desire; it has grown to be stable and laser focused, with a strongly defined culture that aligns with its objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so with a heavy heart, I left the first job that I really, truly, deeply loved with every ounce of my being. The first place I felt I unequivocally belonged, where my voice was heard and respected, in order to chase a new challenge that has become a burning desire that consumes my thoughts constantly. I want to be as revolutionary as Johnny when he decided to go against the norm and make a fully remote company; I want to change the way the industry values qualities that are as essential as practical and technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s that; the hardest decision of my career, to leave a company that I love, where I felt like I belonged, in order to try and expose the true nature of ‘culture’ to the world of tech. I aim to continue to be an engineer, however to all recruiters; its 2022, please do not approach me with anything not fully remote. Let’s leave offices and daily commuting in the past where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written a short piece on the easiest decision of my career; joining Hopin, which will be followed by more personal moments that I feel demonstrate why the Hopin Rocketship is as fast as it is; (hint; it wasn’t just because of covid). I hope I can distill the essence of what it felt like to work at Hopin, and the how and why behind why it was simultaneously exhilarating and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Easiest decision of my career</title>
   <link href="https://adilw3nomad.github.io//2022/04/25/easiest_decision_of_my_career/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-25T09:23:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://adilw3nomad.github.io/2022/04/25/easiest_decision_of_my_career</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-easiest-decision-of-my-career&quot;&gt;The easiest decision of my career&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;july-13th-2020-summer-of-covid&quot;&gt;July 13th 2020, Summer of Covid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hey Adil.  Hope you’re doing great despite the bad news earlier. I wanted to point something out now that the process has come to a close with Cutover.   A contact of mine is in the internal team over at Hopin, a video events platform thats gone from 8 people to 80 people in the last 4 months (thanks to lockdown).  They’re looking for people with your skills, and I’m happy to make an intro if you would like me to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the message sent to me by one of the best recruiters I’ve worked with, Dale Player, after having lost a potential position at a company called Cutover for a more senior developer. At the time, I was pretty down about it, although the developer who interviewed me seemed to nervously laugh alot about the role mainly being upgrading to Angular 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had only used Angular briefly at a previous role, and something about the listlessness in his eyes told me that it would be a gruelling job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I naturally felt dejected by the rejection and so I jumped at this new oppourtunity offered to me by Dale. He put me in contact with a chap called Darren Tomlin, and on the 24th of July I found myself in a video interview with Nico Klein and Piotr Sarnacki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-this-real-life-or-is-it-a-fantasy&quot;&gt;Is this real life, or is it a fantasy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an interview unlike anything I had ever experienced. Nico peppered me with questions to assess my Ruby and Rails knowledge, which I stumbled through awkwardly before he hit me with the next question. It was blunt and to the point; he moved from one question to the next with dexterity, while readily giving feedback on my answers and proposing other alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These alternatives are now what I know to be the objectively better way of going about things, however he never made me feel like I got the question wrong. He reminded me of a stern yet fair teacher, (ironic, since I later found out his passion for teaching Maths through a non-profit app!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piotr, the other interviewer, was quieter then Nico, letting him drive most of the questions. I noticed, however, warmth and encouragement in his eyes, even when I gave the “wrong” answer to one of Nico’s questions. This warmth erupted into an inferno of excitement when he spoke of the cutting edge technologies they were planning on using at Hopin, the unique challenges and oppourtunities to be innovative; to use a lanaguage like Rust to create performant services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hear Piotr talk about Rust was &lt;em&gt;electrifying&lt;/em&gt;. Now, to give you some context, I don’t really like Rust that much, but his passion was contaigious and palpable. I used to run a &lt;em&gt;Gust&lt;/em&gt; club at my previous job (what was meant to be a Golang coding club but everyone wanted to do Rust so we made a compromise), and I had a little idea of what made it so revolutionary. Listening to Piotr speak of using it in production, it gave me goosebumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this happened while we all sat in different rooms, in different houses, and I’m pretty sure different countries (Piotr was in Berlin at the time I think, and unless I’m mistaken, Nico wasn’t living in London at the time). Yet I felt like I was in the same room as them, something I remarked to my brother later on who replied,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well at least you saved on the commute if they don’t take you on”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the first time in my career that I was interviewed by two distinctly different developers, who were actively trying to get me to show them my strengths; a stark contrast to my other experiences. Most tech interviews I had up until that point seemed to be a search for my inadequacies; reasons to say &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; or reasons to offer you a lower salary then you expected or were worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two chaps however, with a combined experience quadrupling my own, brought my best qualities; my curiousity and enthusiasm, my lack of ego to my ideas or beliefs, a detachement to my code. Most of all, they say my deep desire to grow, to work alongside passionate, empathetic and talented individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was by far the best interview I had ever had, so much so that I told Darren (foolishly, don’t do this kids) that I wanted this job so badly, I would be willing to take a salary that was lower then the advertised range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first taste of Hopin culture, and I was hooked like Tommy from trainspotting; intoxicated on a combination of admiration of the company and the pride I felt that I was even being considered to join it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;palms-sweaty-knees-weak-arms-are-heavy&quot;&gt;Palms sweaty, knees weak, arms are heavy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 days later, I get a call from Darren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Heya Adil, so here’s the deal mate, I couldn’t get you the salary you wanted unfortunately…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a matter of seconds, my heart sunk to the floor, then jumped back up when i realised there was still an offer coming, just a shittier one then I had hoped for. I audibily groan/sigh, as I start trying to figure out how low I would go to join this company. I just knew I had to be part of it, but man, living is expensive…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…but I did manage to get you 3k more then you wanted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swear to God I jumped around my house, flip flopping betwen  roaring with laughter and cursing out Darren for his perfectly executed prank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So do you want the job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easiest decision of my career; of course I want the bloody job!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
